Georgia Sfakianaki

🖂 gsfakian@uni-bremen.de 🔹 🔇 gsfakianaki.github.io 🔹 in gsfakianaki Nationality: Greek • Date of Birth: 05 March 1991

Personal statement

I am a Ph.D. candidate in Industrial Mathematics with expertise in inverse problems, experienced both in theoretical and computational approaches. I am highly self-motivated and focused on teamwork with excellent communication and organizational skills. My character is defined by analytical thinking and a problem-solving attitude which enable me to always overcome obstacles.

Work experience

Graduate Research Assistant

Institute of Applied and Computational Mathematics, FO.R.T.H.

Study of existing scientific software for eventual application to concrete problems in the field of vascular biomechanics.

Student Internship

Institute of Applied and Computational Mathematics, FO.R.T.H.

Theoretical study and implementation of the Kalman Filter for data processing.

Census Taker

Hellenic Statistical Authority

Conducted interviews with residents in designated areas while adhering to specific guidelines and confidentiality laws.

Education

Ph.D. in Industrial Mathematics

Research Training Group π^3 , University of Bremen

Thesis: "On the connection between sparsity and tolerances in parameter and data space"

Supervisor: Dr. Iwona Piotrowska-Kurczewski

M.Sc. in Applied and Computational Mathematics, (Very Good, B+)

Department of Mathematics and Applied Mathematics, University of Crete

Major in Scientific Computing

Thesis: "Data Assimilation Methods" Supervisor: Prof. Michael Plexousakis

B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics, (Very Good, 7.3/10)

Department of Applied Mathematics, University of Crete

Major in Mathematical Methods and Software Development

Thesis: "Principal Component Analysis"

Supervisor: Prof. Michael Plexousakis

Teaching experience

- o Programming in Python (undergraduate course, tutoring in Greek)
- o Theory of linear inverse problems (graduate course, tutoring in English)
- o Data analysis and inverse problems in engineering (seminar, tutoring in English)

Research interests

o Inverse problems, Tikhonov regularization, scientific computing, data assimilation methods

Heraklion, Greece Jan 2015 — Jun 2015

Heraklion, Greece

Jul 2014 — Sept 2014

Chania, Greece

May 2011

Bremen, Germany

since Nov 2016

Heraklion, Greece

Sept 2014 — Jun 2016

Heraklion, Greece

Sept 2008 — Nov 2014

Languages

- Greek
- o English
- German

Native language
Professional working proficiency
Elementary proficiency

Technical skills

- o **Programming:** experienced in Matlab, Python, basic knowledge of C and Java
- o Scientific tools: basic knowledge of LifeV, SimVascular, ANSA, Gmsh and ParaView
- o Typesetting: experienced in LATEX, basic knowledge of MS Office and Libre Office
- o Operating Systems: experienced both in Unix-based and Windows environments

Workshops

- o "navigare Career Coaching for International Women in Science 2017/2018" A workshop series which covered the following topics:
 - o Fellow compass. Hidden rules of the German academic system.
 - Career paths between academia and economy.
 - o Self-marketing. Strengthening self-awareness and skills.
 - Networking. Building bridges in international environments.
 - o Heartbeat & liverfear. Resilience in stressful communication.
 - o Sustainable dialogues. Professional communication in academic settings.
- o Good scientific practice for (Post) Doctoral Researchers
- o Soft-skills workshop "Team-building & Getting Started" designed for PhD students
- Scientific writing
- Gender and inter-cultural training course

Conference attendance

- Women in PDEs @ Karlsruhe KIT University, Germany
- Franco-German Summer School on Inverse Problems and Imaging University of Bremen, Germany
- Chemnitz Symposium on Inverse Problems Technical University of Chemnitz, Germany (with presentation)
- Annual Meeting of the International Association of Applied Mathematics and Mechanics GAMM 2019
 Technical University of Vienna, Austria
 (with presentation)
- Deep Learning and Inverse Problems Autumn School University of Bremen, Germany

Hobbies

- Watercolor painting
- Yin Yoga